<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Words by ET</title>
    <description>Maker of software, rider of bicycles, lover of handmade things.
</description>
    <link>http://www.erikthorne.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.erikthorne.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 07:58:36 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 07:58:36 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome!</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-this-place&quot;&gt;What is this place?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello friend! I’m glad you stumbled across my tiny site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Erik and I have way more things that I want to accomplish than I have
time to accomplish them. Whatever though, thats a lame excuse for inaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now this site exists primarily as an online
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.erikthorne.com/2000/01/01/resume.html&quot;&gt;résumé&lt;/a&gt;, but there’s so much more to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m interested in getting more involved in network security and what that even
means. So as I explore that world I’ll make sure to post things that I have done
that are interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things you can most expect on this site in the near future are posts about
my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethorne/dotfiles&quot;&gt;dotfiles repository&lt;/a&gt;. I have a lot of
stuff on there that I think is pretty clever (/brushesoffshoulder), and I’d love
to share it with whatever nerd wants to listen. Now I just have to find the
time to write all that…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-keeps-me-busy&quot;&gt;What keeps me busy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;computers&quot;&gt;Computers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love cooking up my own solutions with whatever tools I have at my disposal.
Sometimes its a “I wonder how hard this would be” kind of thought, and other
times its a “I could do that so much better” thought. I run Ubuntu 18.04 as my
personal OS, I stream my music off a plex library which I have hosted off a
frankenserver at my apartment, and I’ve got a million-and-a-half
questionably-finished projects with Raspberry Pi and Arduino platforms. Wanna
work on something together? Toss me a line, I’d at least like to chat about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;biking&quot;&gt;Biking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was a kid I’ve always loved biking. I never did it on any kind of team,
or really in any organized manner, but I started building and working on bikes
with my brothers around the time I was in junior-high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer I found myself in between jobs with a chunk of change, a friend
willing to sublet my apartment, and an irresistible urge to bike day-in and
day-out for as long as I reasonably could. I never studied abroad in College and
I always told myself that I would travel after graduating. This seemed like the
perfect opportunity, and those don’t always come around twice! I headed out of
New York City at the beginning of June. Fifteen days later I was in Chicago!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.erikthorne.com/_img/et_bike_chicago.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;knoxville&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hanging out for a bit with some friends, I took a Greyhound bus to
Knoxville, TN where this lovely picture of me was shot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.erikthorne.com/_img/et_bike_knoxville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;knoxville&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I headed down a less-than-straightforward path to St. Augustine, FL where I
met up with some family to relax after what ended up being ~2,000 miles of
biking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could fill a whole site about the adventures I had along the way, and I could
write even more about what I learned, but no one wants to hear about all that.
It was mostly just pedalling and eating as much food as I fit in my stomach.
There was the occassional life changing moment, but no one wants to hear about
all that, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;climbing&quot;&gt;Climbing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been climbing rocks for almost as long as I’ve been biking, but I have way
less impressive things to share. Here’s a shot of me being a grease-ball in the
City of Rocks, ID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.erikthorne.com/_img/et_city_of_rocks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;knoxville&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sewing&quot;&gt;Sewing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be much more to come on this. Suffice to say I do not like buying new
things if I think I can make them. The number of things that fall into that
category is increasing each year! Someday I would love to make all my own
clothes (at least the casual-wear ones) and all my own bike bags.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.erikthorne.com/2019/01/21/welcome.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.erikthorne.com/2019/01/21/welcome.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CODE Technology</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;chops-as-a-software-engineer&quot;&gt;Chops as a Software Engineer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working at CODE was fast paced, but highly calculated. Small team size forced
all of us to wear many hats and work quickly, while the high volume of patient
data stressed tight security and strict compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing alongside just a few individuals had me interacting with all parts
of the software stack on a daily basis, not to mention the continuous
integration process. Being the first among a group of new-hires granted me
invaluable experience in helping mitigate the growing pains of a small business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most notable project at CODE had me touching nearly all parts of the code
base in a large scale refactor of our data model. The creation of scope of work
and plan of action took me nearly a month by itself! In the end I bolstered my
knowledge of design patterns and gained indispensible experience with the myriad
challenges that a refactor of that scale entails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of my time at CODE I was working heavily in dev-ops, maintaining
a robust suite of in-house tools (primarily Ansible playbooks, bash scripts, and
python scripts) left over from the co-founder. At the time that I inherited this
responsiblity I understood just enough about that stack to operate in the
environment. As soon as I had to begin troubleshooting, which is an
inevitability, I realized I was in over my head. That is the exact environment I
thrive in! Before I knew it I was fixing broken deployement processes and even
augmenting them, making them easier to work with or more fault tolerant. I
conquered the feeling of being overwhelmed, honed my skills with AWS, and
deepened my knowledge of linux systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked away from CODE with strong back end development skills in Java,
general proficiency with AWS networks, and the ability to live and breathe in
the Ubuntu command line. More importantly, I now feel a high level of comfort
being responsible for vast amounts of sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;more-about-the-company&quot;&gt;More About the Company&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collecting Patient Reported Outcomes is crucial for evidence based medicine, but
it is too arduous a task for doctors, nurses, and clinicians to do themselves.
CODE collects outcomes directly from the patient, effectively delivering the
data and analytics that doctors need without disturbing their day-to-day work.
Check out the awesome work CODE does on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codetechnology.com/&quot;&gt;their
website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.erikthorne.com/2018/07/01/code-technology.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.erikthorne.com/2018/07/01/code-technology.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Institute for Inner Peace and Harmony</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;journey-within&quot;&gt;Journey Within&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mindfulness-based empowerment expert Arda Ozdemir designed a mobile application,
Journey Within, which was predicated on the notion that self-reflection is the
best tool for tranquility and healing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;app-flow&quot;&gt;App Flow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application lead user’s to a guided meditation that was suited for their
particular situation. User’s would state how they are feeling and what they are
struggling with in order to arrive at the meditation recording. The fundamental
concept here was to invoke self-reflection for the user as they moved through
the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;development&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was tasked with designing and building out the back end. The rest API served
JSON data to the iOS client via HTTP. The tricky part of the development process
was streamlining data manipulation for the client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.erikthorne.com/2017/03/01/ifiph.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.erikthorne.com/2017/03/01/ifiph.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Public Radio International</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lead a team of engineers to develop a plugin for Medium Editor to be used by
the writers and editors of Public Radio International. I also designed the
structure of the plugin and lead development team in the implementation of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;development&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin was essentially a modal window that would launch within the editor
and allow insertion of stylized media types. JQuery was the primary language
used for development. The plugin allowed writers and editors to create content
for PRI in a what-you-see-is-what-you-get manner. This entailed interaction with
social media API’s as well as other media sources like Vimeo or YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.erikthorne.com/2016/06/01/pri.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.erikthorne.com/2016/06/01/pri.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DatStat</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-budding-software-developer&quot;&gt;A Budding Software Developer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my entry into the world of professional software development. I got a
job at DatStat by convincing the good people there that I’m a quick learner!
They made me put my money where my mouth was with a project-based interview.
That project was my first exposure to SQL databases, MVC architecture, and C#
(which I don’t care for too much these days, more on that later). I rose to the
challenge and had a great time doing so!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I had pretty bad &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&quot;&gt;imposter
syndrome&lt;/a&gt; working at DatStat,
being the youngest person in the office and only having taken two computer
science classes (one of which was in highschool almost 4 years prior). These
fears were regularly quelled my boss each time we did performance reviews.
Inbetween reviews the fear kept me vigilant. I kept a list of “stuff you don’t
know that you should know,” containing tools, phrases, concepts, or anything
that I would hear around the office and not know. (These days I keep this list
for all projects, calling it SYDKBYSK). Each night I would study the items on
the list with the little time I had between homework and the million other
things that I tried do while in college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to apply the concepts I learned in school directly to my work at
DatStat was a tremendous way to cement them in my mind and also learn their
significance in the industry. Before long I found that my coding proficiency and
my ability to contextualize the theoretical world of academia with the practical
world of software development exceeded most of my classmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;work-and-experience&quot;&gt;Work and Experience&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working at DatStat had me building out custom reports for various clients, as
well as integrating their hardware and/ or software with our platform. I also
saw the company build two products from the ground up in an attempt to replace
an existing product providing invaluable experience from an architectural and
business standpoint. Later in my time there we underwent a massive operations
overhaul. Seeing our internal process restructured and fine tuning that process
was similarly educational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DatStat’s software stack was mostly Microsoft-based (which I do not prefer these
days, but I’m no hater). The more important lessons learned from working there
were higher level: how to architecture practical software, how to navigate
legacy code, how to triage issues, and how to allocate time among the
constituents of a software development team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.erikthorne.com/2016/03/01/datstat.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.erikthorne.com/2016/03/01/datstat.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Résumé</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Download a PDF of my resume &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.erikthorne.com/_img/et_resume_2018.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
or sit tight and enjoy this preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.erikthorne.com/_img/et_resume_2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;resume&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.erikthorne.com/2000/01/01/resume.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.erikthorne.com/2000/01/01/resume.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
